<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Ned Faulkner</title><link>https://faulkner-ned.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Ned Faulkner</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-UK</language><copyright>Copyright © 2025, Ned Faulkner</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://faulkner-ned.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>'Dream Job'</title><link>https://faulkner-ned.github.io/posts/dream-jobs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://faulkner-ned.github.io/posts/dream-jobs/</guid><description>&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We often get asked as children, &amp;ldquo;What is your dream job?&amp;rdquo;, I think that’s a really difficult question, especially as you grow up. As kids, we often answer with things like &amp;ldquo;Actor&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Footballer&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Astronaut&amp;rdquo;, or for kids today, &amp;ldquo;YouTuber/Streamer&amp;rdquo; (which always makes me feel old, even in my early 20s). When you hit your teenage years, your responce usually changes to something a bit more grounded, like a job connected to your favorite subject at school or something someone in your family does.&lt;/p&gt;</description><content:encoded><![CDATA[<hr>
<p>We often get asked as children, &ldquo;What is your dream job?&rdquo;, I think that’s a really difficult question, especially as you grow up. As kids, we often answer with things like &ldquo;Actor&rdquo;, &ldquo;Footballer&rdquo;, &ldquo;Astronaut&rdquo;, or for kids today, &ldquo;YouTuber/Streamer&rdquo; (which always makes me feel old, even in my early 20s). When you hit your teenage years, your responce usually changes to something a bit more grounded, like a job connected to your favorite subject at school or something someone in your family does.</p>
<p>Mark Twain allegedly said, <strong>&ldquo;Find a job you enjoy doing, and you will never have to work a day in your life&rdquo;</strong>. That gets echoed a lot to people, but the reality is from my experience that&rsquo;s not true, but that’s okay.</p>
<p>I switched around &ldquo;dream jobs&rdquo; when I was a child and teenager, from Alan Suger style Businessman to Civil Engineer. But around the age of 16, I decided I was going to try and become a professional Software Engineer. I had always studied Computer Science and/or IT throughout my schooling, and it was always my best subject, but I had never fully committed to doing it as a career. I started working hard to achieving that goal and I was fortunate to secure my apprenticeship and enter the workplace at 18. Even now, as a full-time Software Engineer, there is nothing I would rather be doing than Software Engineering. That might change as I get older, but for now, I consider Software Engineering to be my dream job. However,the statement &ldquo;Find a job you enjoy doing, and you will never have to work a day in your life&rdquo; has <em>never</em> come true. Even though I love my company, the team, the industry, and the role I am in, it still feels like work.</p>
<p>Some might say that because it is not my &ldquo;dream job,&rdquo; and that I have limited experience in different roles in the workplace I would agree with the second part, but not exactly with the first. I like, even love, my job, but I still think of it as work, and I believe that is extremely healthy.</p>
<p>Even when you’re working at your dream job, there will always be something that makes it feel like work. It could be the product you’re working on, the technology you’re using, the team, the company culture, or a design choice you just don’t agree with . That does not mean it is not a dream job.</p>
<p>There are days at work when I am just waiting to finish so I can work on my personal projects. Other days, I finish work and think, &ldquo;I do not want to see a single line of code, let alone write any&rdquo;. I love Software Engineering, and my passion and enjoyment are still as strong, or even stronger, than they have ever been. But my professional work is still work.</p>
<p>It is okay to love and feel very fortunate about your job/role but still think of it as work. Even working on my dream project with my dream team and had full control over the project. I am sure there would still be days when I would come home and think, &ldquo;That was a long day at work. I am glad that is over.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Software Engineers, unlike many other trades or roles, often face an unusual expectation to be &ldquo;developing&rdquo; outside of work. There is some truth to that. A lot of developers do, and I am guilty of this as well. However, <strong>that should not be the expectation, and you should not feel bad if you are not</strong>.</p>
<p>I develop outside of work to learn and because I am passionate about it and enjoy working on it. The things I work on at home might not be related to my project at work, or they might be small tools to make my life at work easier that I could not justify including in a sprint, for example. I am not doing it to turn it into a side hustle or to create a new SaaS product that will make me a millionaire once I sell it.</p>
<p>Find something you are passionate about or enjoy, but remember that it is okay to enjoy and be passionate about something without having to turn it into income. There are too many people online trying to tell you that you should turn all your hobbies and interests into side hustle or &ldquo;Gig&rdquo;. It is okay to have hobbies and things you are interested in just for the sake of enjoyment. Whether they might be. Life is hard, and we deserve our small celebrations.</p>
<hr>
]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>